konna koto ii na   dekitara ii na
I wish I had this...   I wish I could do that...
anna yume konna yume  ippai aru kedo
This kind of dream, that kind of dream... There are lots of kinds, but...
minna minna minna   kanaete kureru
Each and every one of them can come true!
fushigi na pokke de kanaete kureru
With his mysterious pocket, he'll make all your dreams come true!
sora wo jiyuu ni tobitai na
I'd sure like to fly about freely in the sky...
"hai! take koputaa"
"All right! Bamboo 'Copter!"
an an an  tottemo daisuki Doraemon
Oh, oh, oh... I love you so much, Doraemon!
The Fishing Hole in My Room
"The Fishing Hole in My Room!"
Awesum, ain't it?!
Wow! You caught that many?!
Yeah! We found a spot at the river behind the
apartment complex where we can catch a ton of fish!
Well... I  did, anyway.
Yeah, but ya' found it 'cuza my awesum skillz.
Let's go back afta
we grab sum lunch!
Yeah!
Doraemon, let's go fishing, too!
Okay! It does sound like fun!
Let's go after we have lunch!
I won't allow it.
Aw... Why?
Nobi-chan, you're the kind of person who trips and
falls in the gutter while just walking down the street.
So going to a river is completely out of the question.
That's right...
Now that she mentions it, what Mom said is spot-on.
Aw... Just once, I'd really like to try and catch a bunch of fish...
I know how you feel.
Hey, that's it!
Almost forgot I had that.
What do you mean, "that"?
Roll-Up Fishing Hole
A Roll-Up Fishing Hole!
What's that?
The river behind the apartment
complex is about 800 meters to the east...
Hm... Maybe a little
more to the south?
Hey! The paper turned into something that looks like water.
That means the river came to your room.
Yeah, but saying the river came here doesn't really...
Whoa!
I'll go get the fishing poles!
You can't go to the river.
We're not going there...!
Don't worry.
Oh... It's fine in that case, but...
I'm going fishing! I'm going fishing!
Didn't I just say
not to go to the river?!
We're not going there...!
We're going to
go fishing upstairs.
Huh?!
Come on...
I'm gonna catch a bunch!
Why don't we have a contest to see which of us can catch the most?
All right...!
I can't catch even
one, tiny, little fish...!
You can't rush these things.
Man, you're so impatient, Nobita-kun.
Sitting and waiting is one of the fun parts of fishing.
But, but... You really gotta catch them one after another, or it's really boring.
Are there even any fish in here?
Hey, careful! You'll fall in!
Oh, so there ARE fish here!
If we can't catch anything with ALL these fish here...
It's gotta be your gadget's fault, Doraemon!
Oh, brother...
You're terrible at fishing,and yet you
jump right in and blame it on my gadget...
So...
Here. Why don't you try using this?
What's that?!
Hand Hook
It's a Hand Hook!
When this hand locates a fish, it will
automatically grab it and catch it for you.
Then, I can fish this time, for sure!
I caught one!
Yeah!
Okay, now it's my turn...!
All right!
Keep on reeling them in!
We're bringing in an even bigger catch than Gian!
Huh? Huh?
This must be... a big one...
Nobita-kun!
It's pretty big!
All right!
Huh? This isn't a big one at all.
Huh... Very weird.
A line?!
I wonder what that is...?
It's Gian!
Man, that scared me!
Gian! Gian!
What happened?! Why'd you dive into the river like that all of a sudden?
I wuz pulled in.
'N I'm sure dat wuz Doraemon and Nobita!
Sure you're not just nodding off?
Wuz dat a dream?
Oh, well...
Let's fish at some other river, or maybe a pond...
Aw... It had just gotten fun, too...
All right! I'm gonna catch a big bunch again!
Why don't we
have another contest?!
Bring it on!
I'm not gonna lose!
Me neither!
I can't catch even
one, tiny, little fish...!
This is strange... We're even using the Hand Hook, too...
Is this really a river or pond?
Doraemon... It's shallow...
This is just a puddle.
Oh, you're right!
Hey, I know!
This fishing hole connects to anywhere, right?
Well, yes... As long as it's a place with water.
In that case, let's fish in the ocean this time!
That's a great idea! The ocean has tons of different kinds of fish, too!
Hm... I guess somewhere in this area would be good...
Wow! Look at the waves! They're so high!
This has got to be the ocean, right?!
Yep. This definitely isn't a puddle.
Lemme see!
There they are!
And this isn't an aquarium, it's the real ocean!
They're all so pretty!
Nobita-kun!
Be more careful!
This is the deep,
deep ocean, you know?!
Oops, did it again...
This is awesome, Doraemon!
There are tons of fish!
Well, yeah. It's the ocean, after all.
But if you fall in or something, you won't get
off the hook as easily as just getting scolded by Mom!
I'll be fine, I'll be fine!
But Nobita-kun, you're the type of person who trips and
falls in the gutter while just walking down the street...
I'm right here, so no matter what happens, even I couldn't...
I knew it. I guess you really do need these, Nobita-kun.
Deep Sea Cream
No matter how high the
water pressure, or how cold the water...
You'll be fine, if you coat your
entire body with this "Deep Sea Cream"!
Air Tubes
Then simply stick these in your nose...
And the "Air Tubes" will make you be able to breathe underwater!
Wow...!
You'll be fine with these, even if you fall into the ocean...!
Hey... I've got this all ready...
So don't you think it's a waste, just sitting in my room fishing?
Well, you may be right...
That's why...
We should...
Yahoo!
Now we can catch as many as we want!
Catching them one-by-one is such a pain.
Couldn't we catch a whole bunch at once?
A whole bunch...?
At once!
Big Light
We can use the Big Light!
I wonder if I caught about 100 of them?
No fair! No fair!
Hurry up and make my Hand Hook big, too!
Here you go!
All right! Go get 'em!
Oh, no!
You caught a shark!
Hey! It doesn't need to reel it in!
Who would go fishing for a shark?!
Looks like it got stuck and can't move.
I'm so tired, I can't move anymore, either...
Whoa! Look at that!
Huh?
It's a sunken ship.
Let's go hide in there for a while.
Okay...
It seems to be a very old ship.
Ah! Hey...
There might be treasure here that sank along with it!
Oh, Nobita-kun...
The chances of there being treasure in these circumstances are-
Whoa!
Treasure!
See? See?!
We lost the big haul of fish we caught back there...
But in exchange, it looks like we just found a big haul of treasure!
Yeah!
This chest is pretty big, so it must be loaded with treasure!
No doubt about it!
Ready, set, lift!
Huh?
What?!
This...
Isn't treasure...
It's an octopus!
It's gonna eat us!
Then I'll eat it before it can eat us!
Doraemon!
Nobita-kun!
M-M-My underwear's coming off!
Just as I thought. There were a lot of dangerous places in the ocean...
It's still after us!
Get back in there! Get back in there!
I know! If I turn the dial on the Roll-Up Fishing Hole...
And set it to a different location...
Man, that was exhausting...
I'm sick of fishing now...
Huh?
Hey... Is this water...
Doraemon! This is hot water!
Really?!
I'm pretty sure I set it to somewhere close to our house, but...
A hot spring must have sprung up!
This is an amazing discovery!
This thing's also a
Roll-Up Hot Spring!
Hot spring! Hot spring! Yippie!
This feels so good!
Why, you two!
Just where did you come in from?!
Uh, no...
You pervs!
So it was a bathtub...
The Time Machine Disappeared!!
"The Time Machine Disappeared!!"
Nobita!
What is it...?
Come here a second.
Yes, Mom!
Oh! What am I going to do with that boy?
How many times do I have to tell you?
Put your things away when you're done playing wi...
Monster! Monster! Monster! Monster!
That went well.
And back in you go!
This "Monster Ball" sure is fun!
Nobita...?!
You really scared me, didn't you?!
Nobita!
There's no use hiding!
Oh?
Strange...
Ha! She doesn't know about the Time Machine being here!
Oh? You ARE here?
Hey, Doraemon.
That was so much fun!
You see, I took the Monster Ball you lent me, and used it on Mom...
What?! You shouldn't use my gadgets to play pranks!
But all she ever does is nag and yell.
If I leave anything out when I'm done
with it, she yells, "pick this up" and stuff.
Mom is absolutely right to be mad at you!
I mean look at that!
You left the door to the Time Machine wide open!
Every single time! You use something, and leave it out.
You open something, and leave it open...!
What's wrong?
The Time Machine's gone!
What?!
I bet you forgot
to put on the brake!
And now it got pushed down the time stream somewhere!
Now that you mention it...
Without that...
We can't go anywhere!
And I can never go back to the future, either!
This is all my fault! What do we do?!
Come on... Crying doesn't solve anything.
Let's just sit and think of a way to get it back.
Yeah! Think about it!
What should we do?
Did you think of something?
How's it going? Anything yet?
Hurry and think of something!
Can you just be quiet?!
Running around going on and on!
This is what we've been dealt!
Dealt...?
Belt...?
The belts!
Did you think of something?
Time Belt
I have some Time Belts!
What's a "Time Belt"?
These can't move change locations, but they have the ability to time travel.
So let's chase after the Time Machine with these!
But we don't know where the Time Machine went, you know?
I have a Time Sensor.
The Time Machine leaves waves along its path in the time stream...
So we can follow those right to it!
Let's go!
It's picked up the Time Machine's waves!
It's flowing farther and farther back in time. Let's get going!
About when are we?
We just went past the 1600's.
We're getting closer!
Only 200 years to go!
100 years!
50 years!
Huh? The waves stopped.
It was just a little farther, too...
Did the Machine take a detour and get stuck in some other time?
For now, let's get out of the time stream.
Whoa!
Oww...
Huh? Where are we?
Like I said, we don't change locations!
This is where your room is, Nobita-kun!
Only we're 1866 years in the past.
Wow! So that means that my house will be built where I'm standing right now?!
So I go down the stairs like this...
And the entryway would be right around here.
The kitchen would be there... And the bathroom would be here!
What are you doing?!
We've gotta hurry and find the Time Machine!
So, where should we look?
I don't know. If I consider the direction of the vortexes in the time stream...
It should have been sent downstream to the west, but...
Anyways, let's just go scout the area!
Okay!
All I can see is grass and trees.
It may be difficult to find from up here in the sky.
I guess all we can do is look for a village and ask someone.
ARE there any villages?
Villages in this era are very small...
So if you don't look carefully, you might miss one.
Even so, I still can't find one...
Huh?
Our Bamboo 'Copters are making weird noises.
Oh, no! The batteries...
Just died!
Oww...
I'll pull out a replacement.
But I don't have very many, so we've got to use them carefully.
Why is Japan so big...?
I wonder if we can actually find it?
No "wondering" about if we'll find it! We HAVE to find it!
Besides, we got into this mess because you're so careless, Nobita-kun!
Huh?
What's that sound?
Shh... Something's coming!
Ah! That scared me!
What just happened?
It looks like something scared them, and they all instinctively ran.
Wonder what it was?
Wait, could it have been the Time Machine?
It might be.
Let's go check it out!
Aw... Let's just stop!
Then wait right here.
What...?!
Wait for me!
What's that sound...?
It sounds like something big and heavy being dragged around.
The trees and grass...
Are all trampled down and torn apart.
What went through here?
Who knows...?
Oh, no! Those are...
What is it?!
Way over there, deep in the mountains...
Huh?
It's the eyes of a
pack of giant monsters!
Are those dinosaurs?!
Don't be ridiculous!
We know dinosaurs went extinct tens of millions
of years before humanity came into existence!
Then what are those things?!
No clue!
Ah! They're coming!
Run!
Make the bonfire much, much bigger!
Momotaro Jirushi's Millet Dumplings!
These will tame the beasts!
But I still feel helpless with just those!
Pull out a bunch more stuff!
Okay...
The Sure-Hit Slingshot!
The Small Light!
The Hypnosis Machine...
And an RC Robot!
That's still not enough!
Okay...
In that case...!
I'll pull out everything I think we can use!
All right! If you're gonna come, then come and bring it on!
But if possible,
please DON'T come!
I didn't get enough sleep, so I'm really dizzy.
And in the end, they didn't come out, anyway...
Well, it's best that they didn't come out, but what were they, anyway...?
Should we look upstream, downstream, or go across?
Any of those is fine, let's just use the Bamboo 'Copters.
No! I don't have many left, so if we can do it ourselves...
Huh?
Oh...?!
All right! Some chopsticks came floating downstream!
Well, of course the chopstick float.
They're made of wood, after all.
That's not what I meant. Chopsticks floating downstream...
Is a sign of people living upstream, right?!
Let's get moving!
Hey, wait for me!
Hurry up, hurry up!
It's a village!
If we ask there, we might figure something out.
Hey! Hey!
Maybe there's no one here.
Yeah, it's awfully quiet...
It's all gloomy and
gives me the creeps...
Huh?
Someone's crying.
And it sounds like a girl.
Excuse me..
Why are you crying?
What?!
Hey, I don't know what he's saying.
Oh, I get it.
Japanese in this time was different from modern Japanese.
Translation Konjac
So here's a Translation Konjac!
If we eat some of this, we can understand his words.
Okay, let's start over.
What happened to you?
T-That raccoon just spoke!
Don't be rude! I'm NOT a raccoon, I'm a cat-model robot!
Ro...bot...?
Oh, yes...
I see. This be a magical, transformed raccoon.
Moving on, what happened to everyone?
We have angered him.
We have earned the wrath of the Eight-Headed Serpent...
The Eight-Headed Serpent?!
What's that?
You've never heard of it?
It's a ancient mythological snake monster with
eight heads, and is said to be as big as a mountain!
Eight heads?
Hey! Could that be the thing with red eyes we saw last night?
It might be.
But to think that such a monster is real...
It happened about 6 months ago...
The serpent suddenly appeared, and rampaged through our village.
Ever since then, the serpent will often appear and begin rampaging anew.
Our men fought back, but they were no match for it...
And so, in order to appease the serpent's anger...
We are going to offer my daughter as a sacrifice to it tonight.
That's awful!
Really, really awful of you!
However, this has already been decided upon by the village.
No...
Please forgive us.
This is for the safety of our village.
You can't do that!
We... will destroy the serpent!
Nobita!
Just leave it to us.
Oh, mighty Eight-Headed Serpent! We humbly offer you a sacrifice!
Please spare us our lives, and do not lay waste to our village!
Okay, now flee to safety!
If you hesitate,
the serpent will get you!
I wonder if this serpent will really come?
Hey... Is this really going to work?
Like I told you before, according to the legend...
A man known as Susanoo-no-Mikoto...
Let the Eight-Headed Serpent drink a ton of Japanese liquor, or sake...
And once it was completely drunk...
He brought it down in one go.
But can it really be that easy?
Hey, it works
according to the legend.
Don't be so irresponsible!
What else can we do?
We don't know what kind of thing this is.
Besides, YOU'RE the one who said "We will destroy the serpent!"
We got into this mess because YOU always
have to try to look cool in front of girls!
Hey, wait! This is...
The same place we saw last night.
Was the monster from last night the Eight-Heated Serpent, after all?
It's "Eight-HEADED", not "Eight-Heated"!
Now, listen. It has eight heads, right?
It has eight separate heads, so we say it's "eight-headed".
You got it?
It's still weird...
You said it's named that because it has eight separate heads...
But it has seven separations.
That means it should be called the Seven-Headed Serpent.
Anyways! It was decided to call it the Eight-Headed Serpent a long time ago!
But why was that decided?
Come on, why? Why? Why?
Come on, why?
Gah! Now's not the time to be worrying about that...
Ha! You're scared!
Cause you can't think of an answer!
T-There it is!
Hey, what about our plan?!
Oh, yeah...
Here goes nothing!
Oh, mighty serpent...!
Here's some nice, delicious sake.
Go on, help yourself to it.
All right! It's drinking it, exactly according to plan!
And now the serpent's completely drunk!
It's not drunk at all!
I guess it's no use.
Don't just run! Use Momotaro Jirushi's Millet Dumplings!
Oh, yeah!
Momotaro Jirushi's Millet Dumplings!
Take this, and this, and that!
Oh, no! They had
absolutely no effect!
Why?
I don't know!
Doraemon, use some kind of gadget!
The Sure-Hit Slingshot!
And the Small Light!
No way!
They didn't work!
The Hypnosis Machine!
And the Air Pistol!
Not even one of them worked!
Since it comes to this, we need to...
Run!
It's a thicket of grass! Run into it!
That's it! It's getting confused!
Nobita-kun?
I'm lost...
Nobita-kun!
Nobita-kun...!
Whoa!
It's the Monster Ball! And the Time Machine!
So that's it!
Huh?
That was an illusion created by the Monster Ball.
That's why none of my gadgets had any effect on it.
But that means someone had to have pushed
the "Eight-Headed Serpent" switch, right?
A monkey or something must have played with it.
So the Time Machine drifted down and landed here six months before us?
Exactly.
Oh. So it was all an illusion!
And everyone got all worked up about it, too.
What are you talking about?!
YOUR carelessness is what caused all of this in the first place!
Nobita!
Oh, it's that girl!
No! We're going home!
Aw...
I brought down the serpent and all...
So I wanted to hear her say
"Wow, Nobita-san! You're so wonderful!"
"Brought down the serpent"?!
Are you even thinking about how much
trouble you caused the people in that village?!
Regardless, we can't risk changing history any more than we already have!
Come on, hurry!
Okay, okay... I got it.
Nobita...?
Nobita?
Nobita...
Honestly! You leave everything laying around!
You better start being more tidy and cautious from now on!
I got it the first time you said that.
You don't need to keep repeating.
More importantly, why did they call it
"Eight-Headed" when there are only seven separations?
Come on, tell me! Why? Why? Why?
Remember How You Felt That Day!
"Remember How You Felt That Day!"
WAKE... UP!
What time do you think it is?!
Oh, no! I'm late, again!
I'm gonna get scolded again!
I'm gonna have to stand in the hall again!
You never learn, and keep doing the same thing morning after morning...
This is really getting sickening.
Man... You're right. This has gotten sickening.
Anything and everything has gotten sickening.
"Anything" is taking it a little too far...
I know! I'll just stop going to school!
What was that?!
Today's school system isn't geared towards me!
So even if you try to stop me, Doraemon...
Or my teacher gets mad at me...
Or my parents cry...
I'm dropping out of school today!
No matter what might have happened, that's completely absurd!
Huh? What?!
I'll start writing up my
"Dropping Out of School Notice" right now!
What kind of stupid things are you saying?!
What kind of stupid things are you causing a commotion about?!
U-Um... Well, um...
Nobita-kun said he wasn't going to go to school, so...
Oh, that's fine.
What? Huh?!
Because today's Sunday.
Oops...
No, um... Well...
Well, anyway...
Sorry.
Enough of this! Get downstairs and eat your breakfast!
It's a real pain if I can't clean things up!
Yes, Mom!
Mom's in a really bad mood this morning, isn't she?
Huh?
So that's why!
Mom and Dad are fighting!
How about we go to Shizuka-chan's house?
Even if I went, it's nothing special...
I'm sure it'll be fun!
Man, everything's SO boring...
I just repeat the
same thing everyday...
I'm tired of it.
Meaningless.
Everything's meaningless...
It's all the the same plain, predictable old rut...
This is really getting out of hand...
Oh, I know!
I'll use this on him!
First-Time Stamp
The First-Time Stamp!
All right, all right!
For now, let's just go to Shizuka-chan's house!
Shizuka-chan!
We came to play!
But even if I talk to Shizuka-chan,
it's still the same, old thing...
Come on, now...
Is that Nobita-san and Dora-chan?
First-Time...
Stamp!
H-Hey!
Welcome!
You're... Shizuka-chan?!
Well, yes... But why do you ask...?
S-She's SO cute!
I've liked her
even up to now...
But Shizuka-chan hasn't
seemed this attractive since...
What happened to you?
You're acting like it's the first time we met...
Wow!
That voice...
It's so entrancing!
I can't believe it!
To think that I have such a wonderful girl for a friend!
You're over exaggerating.
This game is so much fun, isn't it?
But it's the one we always play...
Haven't you already read that dozens of times?
Nobita-kun, would you like to have lunch with us?
Lunch with Shizuka-chan's family!
This is like a dream.
I'll gladly eat with you all!
I just threw together some random side dishes we had on hand, though.
Not at all! They all have a such new taste, and they're so delicious!
Wow!
I never realized the sunset was this beautiful!
Oh, I'm so happy!
I'm really jealous of you, Nobita-san.
You're like a small child who's curious about
and can get engrossed in everything...
Today was a really fun day!
That's great!
'Ey! Nobita!
Huh?
Ya' skipped out on our game t'day!
I bet you forgot again, didn't you?!
Gian! Suneo!
Look at those round, kind eyes! And that strong, protective body!
What sharp lips! And such a unique hairstyle!
I have such wonderful friends!
Wut's wit ya'?!
Yer creepin' me out!
Nobita's really
being weird today...
Looks like this has a REALLY long-lasting effect...
First-Time Stamp! Stamp!
Nobita! Yer such a
tru friend o' da heart!
Let's be friends forever!
Wow!
It's a dog!
It's wagging it's tail!
And it has it's
tongue sticking out!
'N it has really fluffy fur!
Dogs are amazing!
Maybe this is
a bit TOO strong...
Man, thank goodness that thing's effects finally wore off.
If I had been all mushy-gushy with Gian and Suneo any longer...
I don't know if I could have put up with it.
Sorry, sorry. But isn't the First-Time Stamp pretty amazing?
Just by stamping someone...
They can experience anything, as if it's their first time.
We're home!
What's wrong with you?!
No, what's
wrong with you?!
That was something that happened a long, long time ago...!
But you still did it, right?!
But, still...
No buts!
They're still fighting...
Hey, why don't we try using this on them?
Fine, I don't care anymore!
Fine, do whatever you want!
Hmph!
I never knew you were that kind of person way back then...
I thought you were so much kinder and sweeter...
Same to you!
When we were newlyweds, you were so much more quiet and innocent.
Oh, I'm so blessed!
To think I have such a wonderful woman as my wife...
I think so, too!
I don't think there's a man in this world more handsome and reliable than you!
Oh, Darling!
Honey!
Isn't that great!
I'm going to stamp you with the
First-Time Stamp again tomorrow morning!
That way, you'll be able to feel like going to school!
You got it?!
Hey, are you listening to me?!
What on Earth is
he thinking about...?
So at first, everything feels
so new and emotional, huh...?
I wonder how I felt when I first went to school?
I wonder if I
was excited about it...
No, no way
that could be true.
All right. I'll go check with the Time Machine.
I'll go back to the day before I started elementary school...
Someone's running around, and sounds happy...
It sounds like a little kid.
What are they doing up so late at night...?
Oh...? It's me, back when I was little.
Yay!
Come on now,
it's time for beddy bye.
He's been wearing his backpack
everyday, and he's really excited about this.
Daddy.
When I go to school, I'll be able to make
a whole big bunch of friends, right?
Yes, I think so.
And Teacher will teach me all kinds of neat things, won't he, Mommy?
Yes, that's right.
Wow! I can't wait!
Come on sweetie, take off your backpack.
Okay, Mommy.
I'm going to school! I'm gonna go to school!
Yes, you are.
Okay, time to close those little eyes so you don't oversleep tomorrow.
Okay! Good night, Mommy.
Good night.
Time sure flies, doesn't it?
It seems like just yesterday he was our new, little baby.
And now he's already an elementary-schooler.
I hope Nobita will always think school is a fun place.
I couldn't help but be excited about going to school way back then...
When...? Why...?
How did I get like this...?
WAKE... UP!
Today's Monday!
What? You're already up...?
No matter what you say today, Nobita-kun...
I'm going to make you go to school for sure, today!
I don't need that!
What?!
He's started being stubborn again!
He won't listen to anything I say!
This is really bad!
Nobita-kun's saying he won't go to school again...
Oh, brother. That again?
Isn't that what he always says?
Oh, come on!
I don't have time for this!
Oh, my! Nobi-chan goes to school this morning, doesn't he?!
That's right! Nobita's going to school!
But he said that he's not going to go to school!
What?!
Hurry, we've got to hurry!
Huh? You're all dressed and have your backpack on.
Are you going to school, after all?
Yep.
I can't help it if I don't like school.
But I want to try my hardest to get through it,
without relying on the power of your gadgets!
Wow! Way to go! That's the spirit!
You have no idea how long I've been waiting for this day to come!
Oh, you... Don't exaggerate.
Nobi-chan!
Huh?
Are you going to
school all by yourself?!
Are you really going to be okay?!
Uh, yeah... I'll be fine...
Oh, wow!
Our little boy's growing up!
How wonderful!
They're so moved...
Just like his first time going!
Look out for cars!
Make sure to look both ways before you cross at the crosswalk!
And make sure to tell your teacher if you accidentally wet yourself!
Stop! You're embarrassing me!